<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ren Lee</title>
    <link>https://pid.ren/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ren Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pid.ren/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Air France Flight 447 - an Operational failure</title>
      <link>https://pid.ren/posts/sre-operational-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pid.ren/posts/sre-operational-excellence/</guid>
      <description>I came across an amazing piece of article over this weekend, one that provided an in-depth analysis of the tragedy of Air France Flight 447, &amp;ldquo;The Long Way Down: The crash of Air France flight 447&amp;rdquo;.
(Disclaimer: I am in no shape or form affiliated with this author or Medium - I simply think this was an astoundingly well done article and I encourage anyone that is interested in systems safety or aviations to have a read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on being an engineering manager, 1 year after (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://pid.ren/posts/reflection-1yr-mgmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pid.ren/posts/reflection-1yr-mgmt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently completed my first year as an engineering manager - specifically on the Site Reliability team for CloudVision as a Service at Arista.
In many ways I&amp;rsquo;m writing this for myself moreso than anything else - a way to reflect on this year that flew by so quickly, to catalogue what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, to look ahead into next year. I also hope this helps anyone that is considering to step into management, not as a way to discourage, but rather to encourage by sharing lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Single Most Important Vocabulary in SRE</title>
      <link>https://pid.ren/posts/single-most-important-vocab-in-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pid.ren/posts/single-most-important-vocab-in-sre/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve started my career in software engineering, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been obsessed with one question in mind &amp;mdash; what can go wrong?
💭 What can go wrong with the code I just wrote?
💭 What can go wrong with this framework I am using?
💭 What happens when something &amp;ldquo;goes wrong&amp;rdquo;? Do I have a fallback mechanism? Kill switch?
Sometimes I would even obsess over a single line of code written, thinking of all the ways that one line could break, trying to make it as bulletproof as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software: Looking Beyond Just the Technical</title>
      <link>https://pid.ren/posts/software-looking-beyond-just-the-technical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pid.ren/posts/software-looking-beyond-just-the-technical/</guid>
      <description>(In this article I use the term &amp;ldquo;management&amp;rdquo; loosely to refer to any layer of management, not just managers.)
As a software engineer one of the most critical skillset is being able to discern which tool is the right one for the job that needs to be done. This deserves its own blog post, but in short a software engineer must know what language, features of a language, framework, and tool is the best to solve your problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
